trackvia.com 2017-07-21

# TrackVia Privacy Policy

This privacy policy applies to www.trackvia.com owned and operated by TrackVia, Inc. (“TrackVia”, “We”, “Us”, “Our”). This privacy policy describes how TrackVia, Inc. collects and uses the personal information you provide on our website: www.trackvia.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged TrackVia, Inc.

TrackVia, Inc. complies with the U.S. –Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal information from Switzerland. TrackVia, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view TrackVia, Inc.’s certification, please visit [ **HTTP://WWW.EXPORT.GOV/SAFEHARBOR/**](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/).

TrackVia, Inc. participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. TrackVia, Inc. is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s  **[Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list)**.

TrackVia, Inc. is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. TrackVia, Inc. complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, TrackVia, Inc. is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the **  U.S. Federal Trade Commision **.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, TrackVia, Inc commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Private Shield policy should first contact TrackVia, Inc at: [privacy@trackvia.com](mailto:privacy@trackvia.com).

TrackVia, Inc has further committed to cooperate with EU data protection authorities (DPAs) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning human resources data transferred from the EU in the context of the employment relationship. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact the EU DPAs for more information or to file a complaint. The services of EU DPAs are provided at no cost to you.

In certain situations, TrackVia, Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at  **<https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>**. 

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the  **[Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome)** , you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for the services offered by TrackVia, Inc. (the “Services”) and for this website. TrackVia reserves the right to amend this Privacy Statement at any time. TrackVia will notify all users of material changes to its privacy practices. TrackVia will contact users via an email notice to the user and/or a prominent notice posted within the message center of the user’s account 30 days prior to implementing the change. Only the current Privacy Statement is deemed effective, so please review this Privacy Statement periodically.

1\. We do not reveal any personal information that we collect about you, nor any information or data that you store in your Account, to anyone else. We will share your personally identifiable information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy.

During the registration process, TrackVia collects personally identifiable information (Required Information: First Name, Last Name, Email Address and Optional Information: Organization Name and Phone Number) from the Subscribing Organizations and their Users. Individuals who sign up are also required to create a user name and password for their account. TrackVia uses this information to communicate with organizations during the demo period via email and phone outreach to help get organizations up and running. In addition, TrackVia sends a monthly newsletter to all users who have not opted out of receiving email correspondence from TrackVia.

TrackVia may also collect personally identifiable information at other times, such as when responding to product support inquiries. This information is only used to contact the user to help resolve support inquiries. TrackVia may also contact the user via email to announce improvements to the TrackVia interface. In addition, the TrackVia application allows you to store data and information that is personally identifiable, private, or sensitive. TrackVia may use such information in the aggregate only for its own internal purposes. Account administrators also input their Credit Card information (card type, name on card, billing address, city, state, zip, country, card number and expiration date) when signing up for a paying account. Credit card numbers are stored with payment gateway [ **AUTHORIZE.NET**](http://authorize.net/) and no TrackVia employee can see credit card numbers. We will not sell, rent or release a Subscribing Organization’s or User’s personally identifiable information, application data, or stored information to any other party, except at the request of the Subscribing Organization or under certain rare special circumstances such as court order. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies,  **[contact us here](http://trackvia.com/about-us/contact-trackvia/)**.

TrackVia, Inc. collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. TrackVia, Inc. works with its Clients to help them provide notice to their customers concerning, the purpose for which personal information is collected.

We collect information for our clients, if you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the client that you interact with directly. If you are a Client and would like to update your account please,  **[contact us here](http://trackvia.com/about-us/contact-trackvia/)**.

When you download and use our Services (‘TrackVia’ Mobile Application), we automatically collect information on the type of device you use and operating system version. We collect name, work-related information, customer information and email address.

We collect location based information within the application as requested by the application administrator for the purposes of tracking geolocation information as it pertains to record level data. We will only share this information with our mapping provider for the sole purpose of providing you this service.

We do not share your geo-location data with third parties for the purpose of them serving you ads for places in your area. 

You may be able to disallow our use of certain location data through your device or browser settings, for example by disabling “Location Services” for the TrackVia application in device privacy settings or by emailing us at  **[privacy@trackvia.com](mailto:privacy@trackvia.com)**

2\. TrackVia analyzes information about you only on a basis that does not personally identify you. In order to improve our Service, provide content and develop applications and services that are useful to our Subscribing Organizations and Users, TrackVia may automatically gather information on an aggregate basis about the applications, services and pages of the TrackVia application that Users visit and use. A Subscribing Organization’s or its Users’ personally identifiable information cannot be linked to or discerned from any of this information. TrackVia may also use demographic information and profile data about Subscribing Organizations and Users for these purposes.

3\. TrackVia does not use personally identifiable information to track site visitors. However, once a visitor chooses to create a demonstration account, then TrackVia is able to link a customer’s personally identifiable information (First Name, Last Name, Email Address, Organization Name and Phone Number) via a cookie. In order to offer our Services and to enable certain application features and functionality, TrackVia uses cookies. Cookies are used to determine when a users’ account has been inactive for four hours. For security purposes, TrackVia automatically logs users out of an account that has been inactive for over four hours. Cookies are also used to identify IP addresses of site visitors enabling us to determine site pages visited. This information is only used internally to identify opportunities to improve our website and application.

If you choose to use our referral service to inform someone about our site, we will request their name, email address, company name, and phone number. We will automatically send the person a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. TrackVia stores this information for the sole purpose of contacting them and tracking the success of our referral program.

All individuals may contact us at [ **privacy@trackvia.com**](mailto:privacy@trackvia.com) to request that we remove their information from our database.

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

We TrackVia, Inc. and our partners use technologies such as cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking  **[here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/)**  (or if located in the European Union click  **[here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)** ). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile application.

4\. Internally, we restrict access to all Subscriber information to employees who need access to it to do their jobs. These employees include those engaged in customer support activities or those providing custom services purchased by Subscribing Organizations. These employees are limited in number, and are committed to our privacy and security policies. Any employee who violates our privacy and/or security policies is subject to possible termination and civil and/or criminal prosecution.

5\. Newsletters are sent to users on a monthly basis. Newsletters are sent via email to the account administrator’s registered email address. All email correspondence sent from TrackVia includes an opt-out link at the bottom of the newsletter. All individuals who opt out are automatically removed from future email distribution lists. Users may also send a letter to TrackVia at 1675 Larimer Street, Suite 500, Denver, CO 80202 requesting removal from our email list, or users may call 303.278.1223 to ask for their name to be removed. We will then remove the user’s email address from our mailing list.

6\. Legal Disclaimer.

In certain situations, TrackVia, Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website.

If TrackVia is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information.

7\. Use of Service Providers.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

TrackVia, Inc. may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Clients.

8\. Updating Your Personal Information.

TrackVia, Inc. has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, who seeks to correct, amend, delete inaccurate data or withdraw consent to further contact should direct his/her query to TrackVia, Inc.’s Client (the data controller). If the Client requests TrackVia, Inc. to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 days.

Upon request TrackVia, Inc. will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. You can email [ **privacy@trackvia.com**](mailto:privacy@trackvia.com) ** ** to request updates, corrections, or deletions to your personal information. Updates, Corrections and Deletions to personal information can also be made via post by sending your request to TrackVia at 1675 Larimer Street, Suite 500, Denver, CO 80202.

You may also log into your password-protected TrackVia account and update your personal information by clicking on the My Info link in the right hand side of your account. Make the necessary updates, corrections or deletions and click update user information. Your user information will be updated immediately.

You may also change your billing information within your account by clicking on the Billing Link in the upper right hand corner of your account. Go to the Credit Card Info tab and click on the Edit Credit Card Link. Update or correct your information and click Update Credit Card Information to save your changes.

All change requests submitted via mail or email will be made within 30 days of receiving the request. All changes made within your TrackVia account to the My Info or Billing section will be made immediately when you click the update button.

We will retain your personally identifiable information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. TrackVia, Inc. will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. We will retain and use your personally identifiable information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

9\. Data Transmission.

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be totally secure, and there is a risk that data could be intercepted or interrupted during Internet transmission. TrackVia cannot warrant the security of any information Subscribing Organizations or Users transmit to or from our online services, and Subscribing Organizations and Users do so at their own risk.

The website uses SSL encryption to transmit sensitive information (such as credit card information). All data and billing information is transmitted over the Internet via SSL Encryption secured by Verisign.

10\. Testimonials.

We post customer testimonials on our website which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer’s name. We do obtain the customer’s consent prior to posting the testimonial along with their name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [ **privacy@trackvia.com**](mailto:privacy@trackvia.com).

11\. Blogs.

If you use a bulletin board, blog or chat room on this website, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. To request removal of your personally identifiable information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [ **privacy@trackvia.com**](mailto:privacy@trackvia.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personally identifiable information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

12\. Additional Information

Links to Third-Party Sites  
Our Site includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of ours. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

Social Media Widgets

Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook and Twitter buttons and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

TrackVia, Inc. | 1675 Larimer Street, Suite 500 | Denver, CO 80202  
Phone: 303.278.1223  
Email:[ **privacy@trackvia.com**](mailto:privacy@trackvia.com)  
Effective Date: November 8, 2016
